Inventory of the Textile Collection, 1885 - [ongoing]
Textile Collection, 1885 - [ongoing]
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.).
1000-5
52
36
The textile collection contains shirts, hats, commencement robes, sweaters, uniforms, and other apparel related to Wesleyan University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Acquired from numerous donors. See Special Collections & Archives for details.
Collection Overview
The textile collection contains shirts, hats, commencement robes, sweaters, uniforms, and other apparel related to Wesleyan University.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is not arranged. Items are added as they are acquired.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--History.; Textiles.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - David P. Weber, class of '86 t-shirts
    - Light green Zonker Harris Day West College 1982 t-shirt (Box 1)
    - Blue and green tie-dyed Zonker Harris Day 1984 t-shirt with pink star
    - Yellow and pink tie-dyed Zonker Harris Day 1984 t-shirt with pink star
    - Dark blue Uncle Duke Day / West College / Wesleyan U. / Oct. 24, 1981 t-shirt
    - Pale yellow Duke Day t-shirt with Uncle Duke
    - Yellow and dark green t-shirt with surreal graphics
    - White Retire Regan / Feminist House t-shirt
    - Orange Wesleyan University fall Ball 1984 t-shirt
    - Yellow, pink, blue, tie-dyed Uncle Duke Day 1981 t-shirt
    - Light yellow Wesleyan University / It wasn't a job. It wasn't even an adventure. t-shirt
    - Grey Universitas Wesleiana / Who's Watching Us Now? t-shirt, 1984
    - Naples yellow Zonker Harris Day '85 t-shirt (Box 2)
    - White and black Niezsch Factor baseball tee
    - Red long-sleeved Niezsch Factor t-shirt
    - Yellow and purple t-shirt with Russian text
    - Pink April Fools '85 t-shirt
    - Black Purchase '84 (Purchase Frisbee Cup) t-shirt
  - Orange tie-dyed Project Quezaltenango Donde Iremos t-shirt (Box 3)
  - Charcoal The Muse Concerts / A Non Nuclear Future t-shirt
  - Burgundy Ultimate Bowl Athens, GA April 17-18, 1982 t-shirt
  - Light blue Nietzsch Factor t-shirt
  - Charcoal People Can Make a Difference / Reverse the Arms Race / Nuclear Resistance Group t-shirt
  - Fuchsia Ultimate Frisbee Marathon for Hunger Action, Vassar College, 1987, t-shirt
  - Navy blue Alternative Radio 91.3 FM Stereo University of Hartford t-shirt
  - Navy blue International Frisbee Association (IFA) t-shirt
  - Black Niezsch factor t-shirt with bright pink graphic of nude Nietzsche
  - Red Wesleyan / Not:…and it's NOT an all girl's college outside of Boston t-shirt (Box 4)
  - White Wesleyan University t-shirt with purple letters, mid 1990s
  - Red Wescrew t-shirt, early 1990s
  - Red Wesleyan University t-shirt; back: Weslead Wescape with cardinal
  - Grey Wesleyan University, Middletown Connecticut t-shirt; back: Wesleyan NOT:... and it's NOT an all girls college outside of Boston
  - White WesWell t-shirt
  - White Wesleyan Class of 1989 t-shirt (Box 5)
  - White Freeman Athletic Center Grand Opening March 31, 1990 t-shirt
  - White Wesleyan Orientation '89 t-shirt
  - White No Brain No Gain t-shirt
  - Black Wescrew t-shirt with red text
  - Red Wesleyan University t-shirt with black text
  - White Super Foss Day '98 Wesleyan University t-shirt (Box 6)
  - Grey Wesleyan v-neck, 2001
  - White Congratulations on 25 Years of Service at Wesleyan University t-shirt; back: Faculty / Staff Appreciation Picnic 2001 Class of 1976
  - White t-shirt with Wesleyan crest and Universitas Wesleiana
  - Black Capitol Cardinals / We Score More t-shirt with angry volleyball-wielding cardinal
  - Red Class of '87 Wesleyan University / Graduation / The World Awaits t-shirt
  - White Congratulations on 30 Years of Service at Wesleyan University t-shirt; back: Faculty / Staff Appreciation Picnic 2001 Class of 1971 (Box 7)
  - White Get Zonked Zonker Harris Day 2000 t-shirt
  - Green tie-dyed Weshop / Convenience, natural and bulk foods t-shirt, 2003
  - Maroon Hewitt t-shirt; back: Top 10 Reasons to Live in Hewitt...
  - White Skidmore Basketball 2000 Tip-Off Tournament t-shirt
  - White t-shirt, Westonecoldsober
  - White ringer tee with stork carrying a TC Frisbee; back: When seven hot people come together, the stork brings them a Frisbee (Box 8)
  - White Citius Altius Fortius t-shirt; back: Wesleyan Class of 2003 and crest
  - Grey Wesleyan University Residential Life 2001-2002 t-shirt
  - White Camp on Borrowed Time t-shirt, senior thesis of Lin Manuel Miranda, 2002
  - Red Wesleyan in Hebrew t-shirt 2003
  - Bright green t-shirt with black Wesleyan crest 2001-2003
  - Brown The Art Library…a great place to work t-shirt (Box 9)
  - Bright green t-shirt with black Wesleyan crest
  - Red Wesleyan University t-shirt with Wesleyan crest
  - White Wesleyan University t-shirt with crest; back: Middletown - Connecticut - 1651 - 350 - 2001
  - White Get Zonked Westco '99 t-shirt; It would drive your mom to debauchery
  - White Iso-2001 t-shirt
  - Yellow Welcome... Wesleyan t-shirt with abstract picture of campus (Box 10)
  - White Howe Cup 1993 shirt with pictures of rackets and balls
  - White Wesleyan University 1986 t-shirt; It wasn't a job. It wasn't even an adventure.
  - Black Cultural Rhythms / Community of Different Drummers t-shirt; Wesleyan University Student of Color Prefrosh Program April 17-19, 1996
  - White Wesleyan Debate t-shirt; back: We do it standing up in 8 minutes in front of a judge
  - White Toga Party '94 Alpha Delta Phi Wesleyan University t-shirt with two Romans with foaming tankards of beer
  - ??? Society white t-shirt with Wesleyan crest; back: ??? Society First Annual Convention, Middletown Chapter, Wesleyan University, Middletown, Connecticut / August 26-29, 1993 (Box 11)
  - White Wesleyan University t-shirt, listing aspects of Wesleyan and Wesleyan life
  - White Wesleyan t-shirt
  - Red Wesleyan Goes to Washington t-shirt, March 7, 1983, National Student Lobby Day
  - Gray Wesleyan t-shirt
  - White Nescac 96 football t-shirt with football helmets
  - White Middletown's Youth: A Celebration of Us shirt (Box 12)
  - White v-neck t-shirt
  - White Wesleyan football t-shirt Refuse to Lose / We will beat Williams
  - White Christmas in April / Greater Middletown t-shirt
  - Black Hi/Lo Rise '01-02 t-shirt
  - White Wesleyan 03 Hockey t-shirt, 2004
  - Blue tie-dyed Nicolson 2002 t-shirt, Only 83 ½ steps from Mocon to the Bathroom with picture of toilet
  - White Senior Woodframe 2004 t-shirt, Where's the Party?
  - Red Wesleyan (repeated in various fonts) t-shirt
  - Grey Weswings t-shirt, anthropomorphic drumsticks, Chicken with Attitude
  - Red class of 1980 t-shirt, Wesleyan / 10th Reunion
  - Red Wesleyan Dance Dept. sweatshirt, early 1990s (Box 13)
  - Black zip-up hoodie, 2002
  - Red v-neck with 222 Church St. (Box 14)
  - White rugby shirt, 2003
  - Red rugby shirt, 2003
  - Red Summerfield v-neck, 2003
  - Black Wesleyan swim cap (Box 15)
  - Red Wesleyan hockey jersey, 19
  - Black Asic shorts
  - Men's/women's crow uniform, 1999-2002
  - Black hoodie with Wesleyan crest
  - Knitted blue football helmet, 1885-1888 (Box 16)
  - Black "Wesleyan" scarf, 2002-2003
  - Black stocking cap with cardinal, 2000-2002
  - Black and red reunion jacket, 28, Earl L. Gaylor, class of 1928 (Box 17)
  - Black reunion sweater with red W, Earl L. Gaylor, class of 1928
  - Red, black, yellow banner with '89 (Box 18)
  - Black banner with '93 and red Wesleyan University '93 pin
  - Red and black Cardinals Wesleyan banner with bickering cardinals in Wesleyan sweaters
  - Black Wesleyan pennant, text red
  - Large red Wesleyan banner, red text
  - Large black Wesleyan banner, red text, from Den Jennings, class of '36
  - Fringed black Wesleyan 1927 square of cloth (Box 19)
  - Red Wesleyan pennant with Wesleyan seal
  - White Wesleyan University tote bag with crest
  - Red and black Wesleyan University tote bag
  - Red and black flag of the Old Commons Club
  - Green, yellow, and purple Ivy Club flag
  - US flag, 48 stars
  - Red, yellow, blue, white service flag
  - Two red strips of felt with circled '07 in black
  - White strip of cloth with "Strike" and fist in red
  - Maroon and pink ribbon, 93 pin in center
  - Wood and paper fan with silver/white painted flowers and Wesleyan pennant in red and black
  - White sack
  - Off-white tassel
  - Two red hats with black band (Box 20)
  - Black beanie
  - Brown beanie, Simms written inside, 1912
  - Red and black cap, 14
  - Two white bucket hats, Wesleyan Seniors
  - Khaki bucket hat, Wesleyan '34's 50th
  - Black beanie, 63
  - Red beanie, skull image
  - White conductor's cap, 14, Holmes written inside
  - Black Wesleyan Hockey baseball cap (Box 21)
  - Black and red Wesleyan University cap with crest; back: 1991
  - Black cardinal cap; back: WESeniors
  - Black cardinal baseball cap
  - White Go Wes conductor's cap; Wesleyan seal on top
  - White Wesleyan conductors cap; Foss Hill Five Six Seven Annex '84 on top; back: Always on Top
  - Two black W baseball caps
  - Black and red beanie, Willard Lockwood
  - Navy blue Wesleyan University W visor
  - White W/Freeman Athletic Center baseball cap
  - Black graduation cap, Elizabeth P. Bransfield, Class of 1907 (Box 22)
  - Black graduation cap, given by Paul DiSanto
  - Red and black MA hood, 1888, Frank P. Upham
  - Red and black MA hood
  - Red, black, and white MA hood
  - Yellow, black, red hood brought in by Chriskylin
  - Caleb Winchester's gown
  - Black commencement robe, Will Beach, class of 1926 (Box 23)
  - White Event Support Wesleyan University ringer tee with red cardinal and lettering; back: ITS Event Support (Box 25)
  - Grey Wesleyan hoodie with black lettering
  - Black Middletown Flatball Association hoodie with red lettering
  - Grey W sweatshirt, red text (Box 26)
  - Grey Wesleyan sweatshirt, black text
  - Red Wesleyan University Orientation 2004 t-shirt with crest (Box 27)
  - Two white Wesleyan University Class of 2005 Senior Gift t-shirts with crest; back: names listed
  - White Wesleyan Athletics t-shirt with cardinal in front of W
  - White long-sleeved Senior Woodframe 2006 Wesleyan University t-shirt with house
  - Pink poorly tie-dyed Get Well t-shirt; back: Know Your ABCs... WesWell
  - White Wesleyan Football t-shirt with football and cardinal
  - Cardinal t-shirt (Box 28)
  - Navy blue NESCAC CHAMPIONSHIPS 2001 t-shirt; back: volleyball and schools listed on the back
  - Red Molecular Biology & Biochemistry MB&B t-shirt
  - Yellow t-shirt with Wesleyan crest; back: Event Staff
  - White long-sleeved t-shirt; back: Oddfellows Playhouse Neighborhood Troupes Program with boy wearing sandwichboard sign
  - Blue and orange baseball t-shirt, Buenos Aires Argentina Flagso Facultad Latino-Americana de Ciencias Sociales
  - Grey Wesleyan t-shirt, black text
  - Grey Wesleyan sweatshirt with white and maroon lettering (Box 29)
  - Red Wesleyan W jacket with white piping and Wesleyan University on sleeves
  - Black and white mesh WESeniors cap, text in white and red (Box 30)
  - Red Wesleyan University Orientation 2004 t-shirt, with Wesleyan crest
  - Yellow WWW@iso'05 t-shirt with Wesleyan crest; back: Wesleyan University welcomes the world @Iso
  - Dark green Summerfields polo, red text
  - Grey Wesleyan Football hoodie with cardinal and football
  - Black Wesleyan University, 175 years pin (Box 31)
  - Black Class of 1961 45th Reunion beanie with red lettering
  - Black Wesleyan University polo with red lettering
  - Black baseball cap with white W
  - Maroon Wesleyan University Residential Life 2005-2006 t-shirt with white lettering
  - White Seniors '06 t-shirt; back: Busting out
  - Dark green Summerfields polo with red text
  - Orange t-shirt Ter-qua-squi-cen-ten-ni-al, noun: a 175th anniversary or celebration. Coming soon to your alma mater, Wesleyan crest
  - Black S.W.A.B. t-shirt; back: Survey of Wesleyan Access to Bathrooms 2006
  - Black apron: 1st Annual Thanksgiving Dinner, Wesleyan University (Box 32)
  - White t-shirt. Front: Congratulations on 5 years of service at Wesleyan University; Back: Faculty/Staff Appreciation Picnic 2001, Class of 1996
  - White t-shirt, hand silkscreened with red and green. Text: Foss Fest? Fine By Me
  - Red t-shirt, Wesleyan Tennis
  - Blue t-shirt. Front: WES Swimming & Diving Winter Training 2005; Back: Hurts so good!
  - Black Wesleyan skull cap
  - Black long-sleeved t-shirt. Front: Hewitt; Back: Kiss me I'm Hewish; Sleeve: 2003-2004 Hewitt
  - Black t-shirt, Wesleyan University Dining Services
  - Red t-shirt with cardinal on front. Back: The few...the proud/Wesleyan Swimming & Diving Nescac Championships 2007 with list of women's team members
  - Green t-shirt. Front: Summerfields/Great food perfect balance; Back: Feed the Locals!
  - Red v-neck t-shirt, Wesleyan Dining Services
  - Black t-shirt, Wesleyan University KSA/Korean Student Association with Korean characters on back
  - Red fleece blanket with embroidery: Wesleyan Faculty/Staff Appreciation Picnic 2004
  - Navy blue polo, Wesleyan University Staff (Box 33)
  - Black baseball cap with 175th logo
  - White t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan University Class of 2005 Senior Gift with shield; back: list of names and Beat 93%
  - White t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan Baseball; back: A tradition since 1865
  - White t-shirt hand silkscreened, Nagarote Wesleyan Partnership with logo
  - Long sleeved black t-shirt, Say it Laude with 175th logo
  - Black t-shirt; front: Queer Awareness Days 2003, the Endless Acronym; back has long acronym with other text
  - Red t-shirt with picture of Doug Bennet and some Russian text, sent to the class of 2007 from the Wesleyan Fund
  - Red t-shirt. Back: Wesleyan University/Amnesty International with logo, circa 2007 (Box 34)
  - White t-shirt. Front: WAF; Back: Wesleyan Annual Fund, circa 2007
  - White t-shirt. Front: WAF; Back: Wesleyan Annual Fund, circa 2007. In original plastic wrap in telephone shape.
  - White t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan University with small cardinal logo; back: Orientation '07 with large cardinal logo
  - White t-shirt. Front: DKE/Gamma Phi; back: If you're gunna' be Greek... /Why not be a GOD?/Wesleyan Greek Week '07 with picture of spartan
  - Black t-shirt. Front: 175th Anniversary Wesleyan logo; back: photo of McConaughy Hall, McConaughy Hall, 1962-2007
  - Black drawstring bag with cardinal logo and WESLEYAN, 2007
  - Black polo shirt embroidered on front: Wesleyan Dining/By Bon Appetit, circa 2007-2008
  - Black hooded sweatshirt. Front: cartoon of figure playing frisbee; back: Nietzsch Factor, circa 2007-2008
  - Navy blue t-shirt. Pink writing on front: Beta Theta Pi/Hell Week 2008; back: It's The Best Week EVER with image of campfire (Box 35)
  - Gray t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan cardinal and W, with Wesleyan University above and Lacrosse below
  - White t-shirt. Front: In the/ Heights/ A New Musical; back: W/Richard Rodgers Theatre, New York City/September 5, 2008
  - Teal t-shirt. Front: Image of Abraham Lincoln riding Tyrannasaurus Rex, Hi Rise/Lo Rise
  - Gray t-shirt. Front: Nike swoosh, with Wesleyan/Football and design of football; back: 78
  - White t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan University/Class of/Oh/Nine/Gave to the Wesleyan Fund and Wesleyan shield; back: Did/you?
  - Stocking cap (hat). Red with black band and black W.
  - White t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan University in dark red with image of College Row buildings in black
  - Red child-size t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan/University
  - Pink bra. Signed by approximately 20 men, and marked Bill Higginson/Frosh Burn/Dec. 19, '33
    Donated by Beth Higginson, January 2009.
  - Red felt banner, possibly an arm band. Black oval with black '07 in the center
    Belonged to George Lewis Mylchreest, class of 1907. Donated by Vorrey Mylchreest, August 2009.
  - Small red change purse: Wesleyan Public Safety / 860-685-2345 / Emergency: 860-685-3333 / www.wesleyan.edu/publicsafety
  - White ringer t-shirt. Front: WesHaul / Moving In Made Easier with orange image of College Row.
  - Black and red polo shirt. Front: Usdan University Center embroidered in white thread, and Wesleyan University in white thread on right arm
  - Blue t-shirt. Front: orange design with the letters W, O, and C [Wesleyan Outing Club]
  - White t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan University / Fast*A*Thon in orange. Back: Fast*A*Thon / Thursday, / October 1, 2009 / Sponsored by: / Interfaith Justice League / Muslim Student Association / Haveli / Bon Appetit / Muslim Coalition of CT / University Chaplains / Office of Community Service / SBC / SALD in orange
  - Gray t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan in red lettering with black border
  - Gray sweatshirt. Front: Wesleyan University in maroon lettering with illustration of football. Sleeve embroidered with number 43 in red. (Box 36)
  - Black t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan Dining / by / Bon Appetit in gold lettering
  - White t-shirt. Front: cartoon image of cardinal, with 2010 in blocks. Back: The / Wesleyan / Fund and FEED THE BIRD
  - Red and white windbreaker. Front, right lapel: Wesleyan / Track and Field in black lettering with Wesleyan shield
  - Purple and yellow tie-dyed t-shirt. Front: common moment with Feet to the Fire logo, and Wesleyan University August 29, 2008
  - Red long sleeved t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan / Track & Field in white lettering with W and cardinal logo
  - Black bag with WESLEYAN / UNIVERSITY in white lettering with cardinal logo
  - Black track pants with white and black stripes running down sides. WES in red and white embroidery near right ankle
  - Red and black baseball cap with Wesleyan / University in black embroidery and 57 in white embroidery
  - Black skinny tie with red cardinals, circa 1964-1965
    Donated by James S. Vaughn, class of 1967, February 2010.
  - Black t-shirt. Front: Wesleyan Basketball in white lettering with a white basketball.
  - White sash: Wesleyan / 1940 in red lettering.
  - White t-shirt. Front: Zonker Harris Day 2011 in black lettering with a Doonesbury comic drawing.
  - Red basketball shorts. Each side features an embroidered cardinal in a white jersey with a W making a lay-up (Box 37)
  - Black windbreaker with red stripes on arms. Front left lapel: Wesleyan Soccer embroidered with the number 1.
  - Red sleeveless jersey with diagonal black and white stripes, and Wesleyan on the front.
  - Black t-shirt. Front: Bon Appetit / Management Company in white lettering.
  - Black shorts. Front: Wesleyan / Swimming with a cardinal logo.
  - Black singlet with red and white decoration. Front: Wesleyan.
  - Red and black hooded windbreaker. Front: Track & Field / Cross Country with a cardinal logo.
  - Reversable white and maroon sleeveless basketball jersey. Front: Wesleyan with a basketball; back: 10.
  - Red cotton bookbag. Front: W / 2010 in black.
  - Gray t-shirt. Front: Earth & Environmental Sciences/ Wesleyan University in white, with circular image of Earth on upper half, and the cross section of a tree on lower half.
    Donated by Eric Howard, May 2011.
  - Red windbreaker. Front: Wesleyan / University in white, with two golf clubs and golf ball. (Box 38)